{
  "questions": [
    {
      "type": "creative-writing",
      "passage": "Some schools require each student to participate in an organized school sport chosen by the student. People at these schools argue that athletics is an important part of the educational experience and that there should be a rule requiring participation. Others argue that students should be free to decide whether or not they wish to participate in organized school sports. Write an essay for a classroom instructor in which you take a position on whether participation in organized school athletics should be required. Be sure to defend your position with logical arguments and appropriate examples."
    },
    {
      "type": "multiple-choice",
      "passage": "In the words of Thomas DeQuincey, \"It is notorious that the memory strengthens as you lay burdens upon it.\" If, like most people, you have trouble recalling the names of those you have just met, try this: The next time you are introduced, plan to remember the names. Say to yourself, \"I'll listen carefully; I'll repeat each person's name to be sure I've got it, and I will remember.\" You'll discover how effective this technique is and probably recall those names for the rest of your life.",
      "question": "The main idea of the paragraph maintains that the memory",
      "options": [
        "always operates at peak efficiency.",
        "breaks down under great strain.",
        "improves if it is used often.",
        "becomes unreliable if it tires."
      ],
      "answer": "improves if it is used often."
    },
    {
      "type": "multiple-choice",
      "passage": "Unemployment was the overriding fact of life when Franklin D. Roosevelt became president of the United States on March 4, 1933. An anomaly of the time was that the government did not systematically collect statistics of joblessness; actually it did not start doing so until 1940. The Bureau of Labor Statistics later estimated that 12,830,000 persons were out of work in 1933, about one-fourth of a civilian labor force of more than 51 million. Roosevelt signed the Federal Emergency Relief Act on May 12, 1933. The president selected Harry L. Hopkins, who headed the New York relief program, to run FERA. A gifted administrator, Hopkins quickly put the program into high gear. He gathered a small staff in Washington and brought the state relief organizations into the FERA system. While the agency tried to provide all the necessities, food came first. City dwellers usually got an allowance for fuel, and rent for one month was provided in case of eviction.",
      "question": "This passage is primarily about",
      "options": [
        "unemployment in the 1930s.",
        "the effect of unemployment on United States families.",
        "President Franklin D. Roosevelt's presidency.",
        "President Roosevelt's FERA program."
      ],
      "answer": "President Roosevelt's FERA program."
    },
    {
      "type": "multiple-choice",
      "passage": "It is said that a smile is universally understood. And nothing triggers a smile more universally than a taste of sugar. Nearly everyone loves sugar. Infant studies indicate that humans are born with an innate love of sweets. Based on statistics, a lot of people in Great Britain must be smiling because on average, every man, woman, and child in that country consumes 95 pounds of sugar each year.",
      "question": "From this passage it seems safe to conclude that the English",
      "options": [
        "do not know that too much sugar is unhealthy.",
        "eat desserts at every meal.",
        "are fonder of sweets than most people.",
        "have more cavities than any other people."
      ],
      "answer": "are fonder of sweets than most people."
    },
    {
      "type": "multiple-choice",
      "passage": "With varying success, many women around the world today struggle for equal rights. Historically, women have achieved greater equality with men during periods of social adversity. The following factors initiated the greatest number of improvements for women: violent revolution, world war, and the rigors of pioneering in an undeveloped land. In all three cases, the essential element that improved the status of women was a shortage of men, which required women to perform many of society's vital tasks.",
      "question": "We can conclude from the information in this passage that",
      "options": [
        "women today are highly successful in winning equal rights.",
        "only pioneer women have been considered equal to men.",
        "historically, women have only achieved equality through force.",
        "historically, the principle of equality alone has not been enough to secure women equal rights."
      ],
      "answer": "historically, the principle of equality alone has not been enough to secure women equal rights."
    },
    {
      "type": "multiple-choice",
      "passage": "In 1848, Charles Burton of New York City made the first baby carriage, but people strongly objected to the vehicles because they said the carriage operators hit too many pedestrians. Still convinced that he had a good idea, Burton opened a factory in England. He obtained orders for the baby carriages from Queen Isabella II of Spain, Queen Victoria of England, and the Pasha of Egypt. The United States had to wait another 10 years before it got a carriage factory, and only 75 carriages were sold in the first year.",
      "question": "Even after the success of baby carriages in England,",
      "options": [
        "Charles Burton was a poor man.",
        "Americans were still reluctant to buy baby carriages.",
        "Americans purchased thousands of baby carriages.",
        "the United States bought more carriages than any other country."
      ],
      "answer": "Americans were still reluctant to buy baby carriages."
    },
    {
      "type": "multiple-choice",
      "passage": "All water molecules form six-sided structures as they freeze and become snow crystals. The shape of the crystal is determined by temperature, vapor, and wind conditions in the upper atmosphere. Snow crystals are always symmetrical because these conditions affect all six sides simultaneously.",
      "question": "The purpose of the passage is to present",
      "options": [
        "a personal observation.",
        "a solution to a problem.",
        "actual information.",
        "opposing scientific theories."
      ],
      "answer": "actual information."
    },
    {
      "type": "multiple-choice",
      "passage": "In the words of Thomas DeQuincey, \"It is notorious that the memory strengthens as you lay burdens upon it.\" If, like most people, you have trouble recalling the names of those you have just met, try this: The next time you are introduced, plan to remember the names. Say to yourself, \"I'll listen carefully; I'll repeat each person's name to be sure I have it, and I will remember.\" You'll discover how effective this technique is and probably recall those names for the rest of your life.",
      "question": "The writer believes people remember names best when they",
      "options": [
        "meet new people",
        "are intelligent",
        "decide to do so",
        "are interested in people"
      ],
      "answer": "decide to do so"
    },
    {
      "type": "multiple-choice",
      "passage": "Many people have owned, or have heard of, traditional \"piggy banks,\" coin banks shaped like pigs. A logical theory about how this tradition started might be that because pigs often symbolize greed, the object is to \"fatten\" one's piggy bank with as much money as possible. However, while this idea makes sense, it is not the correct origin of the term. The genesis of the piggy bank is the old English word \"pygg\", which was a common kind of clay hundreds of years ago in England. People used pots and jars made out of this red \"pygg\" clay for many different purposes in their homes. Sometimes they kept their money in one of the pots, and this was known as a pygg bank. Over the years, because \"pygg\" and \"pig\" sounded the same, glaziers began making novelty banks out of pottery in the shape of a pig as a kind of joke. These banks were given as gifts and exported to countries where people spoke other languages and where no one had ever heard of pygg clay. The tradition caught on all over the world, and today piggy banks come in all colors and are made of all kinds of materials, including plastic.",
      "question": "This passage is mainly about",
      "options": [
        "how people in different countries save their money",
        "how people in England made pottery centuries ago",
        "how a common expression began in a surprising way",
        "how an unusual custom got started"
      ],
      "answer": "how a common expression began in a surprising way"
    },
    {
      "type": "multiple-choice",
      "passage": "It is said that a smile is universally understood. And nothing triggers a smile more universally that the taste of sugar. Nearly everyone loves sugar. Infant studies indicate that humans are born with an innate love of sweets. Based on statistics, a lot of people in Great Britain must be smiling because on average, every man, woman and child in that country consumes 95 pounds of sugar each year.",
      "question": "This passage implies that the writer thinks that 95 pounds of sugar per person per year is",
      "options": [
        "a surprisingly large amount",
        "a surprisingly small amount",
        "about what one would expect",
        "an unhealthy amount"
      ],
      "answer": "a surprisingly large amount"
    },
    {
      "type": "multiple-choice",
      "passage": "The wheel has been used by humans since nearly the beginning of civilization and is considered one of the most important mechanical inventions of all time. Most primitive technologies since the invention of the wheel have been based on its principles, and since the industrial revolution, the wheel has been a basic element of nearly every machine constructed by humankind. No one knows the exact time and place of the invention of the wheel, but its beginnings can be seen across many ancient civilizations.",
      "question": "According to this passage, the wheel is an important invention because",
      "options": [
        "it is one of the world's oldest inventions",
        "it forms the basis of so many later inventions",
        "it is an invention that can be traced to many cultures",
        "it is one the world's most famous inventions"
      ],
      "answer": "it forms the basis of so many later inventions"
    },
    {
      "type": "multiple-choice",
      "passage": "Samuel Morse, best known today as the inventor of Morse Code and one of the inventors of the telegraph, was originally a prominent painter. While he was always interested in technology and studied electrical engineering in college, Morse went to Paris to learn from famous artists of his day and later painted many pictures that now hang in museums, including a portrait of former President John Adams. In 1825, Morse was in Washington, D.C., painting a portrait of the Marquis de Lafayette when a messenger arrived on horseback to tell him that his wife was gravely ill back at his home in Connecticut. The message had taken several days to reach him because of the distance. Morse rushed to his home as fast as he could, but his wife had already passed away by the time he arrived. Grief-stricken, he gave up painting and devoted the rest of his life to finding ways to transmit messages over long distances faster.",
      "question": "Morse left the art world and helped to invent the telegraph",
      "options": [
        "because he was tired of painting",
        "because he wanted to communicate with people far away",
        "because of a personal tragedy in his life",
        "because he was fascinated by science"
      ],
      "answer": "because of a personal tragedy in his life"
    },
    {
      "type": "multiple-choice",
      "passage": "Leonardo DaVinci is not only one of the most famous artists in history, he was also a botanist, a writer and an inventor. Even though most of his inventions were not actually built in his lifetime, many of today's modern machines can be traced back to some of his original designs. The parachute, the military tank, the bicycle and even the airplane were foretold in the imaginative drawings that can still be seen in the fragments of Leonardo's notebooks. Over 500 years ago, this man conceived ideas that were far ahead of his time.",
      "question": "The author of this passage is praising Leonardo DaVinci for his:",
      "options": [
        "artistic talent",
        "intelligence",
        "vision",
        "fame"
      ],
      "answer": "vision"
    },
    {
      "type": "multiple-choice",
      "passage": "The Midwest is experiencing its worst drought in 15 years. Corn and soybean prices are expected to be very high this year.",
      "question": "What does the second sentence do?",
      "options": [
        "It restates the idea found in the first.",
        "It states an effect.",
        "It gives an example.",
        "It analyzes the statement made in the first."
      ],
      "answer": "It states an effect."
    },
    {
      "type": "multiple-choice",
      "passage": "Social studies classes focus on the complexity of our social environment. The subject combines the study of history and the social sciences and promotes skills in citizenship.",
      "question": "What does the second sentence do?",
      "options": [
        "It expands on the first sentence.",
        "It makes a contrast.",
        "It proposes a solution.",
        "It states an effect."
      ],
      "answer": "It expands on the first sentence."
    },
    {
      "type": "multiple-choice",
      "passage": "Knowledge of another language fosters greater awareness of cultural diversity among the peoples of the world. Individuals who have foreign language skills can appreciate more readily other peoples' values and ways of life.",
      "question": "How are the two sentences related?",
      "options": [
        "They contradict each other.",
        "They present problems and solutions.",
        "They establish a contrast.",
        "They repeat the same idea."
      ],
      "answer": "They repeat the same idea."
    },
    {
      "type": "multiple-choice",
      "passage": "Serving on a jury is an important obligation of citizenship. Many companies allow their employees paid leaves of absence to serve on juries.",
      "question": "What does the second sentence do?",
      "options": [
        "It reinforces what is stated in the first.",
        "It explains what is stated in the first.",
        "It expands on the first.",
        "It draws a conclusion about what is stated in the first."
      ],
      "answer": "It reinforces what is stated in the first."
    },
    {
      "type": "multiple-choice",
      "passage": "While most people think of dogs as pets, some dogs are bred and trained specifically for certain types of work. The bloodhound's acute sense of smell and willing personality make it ideal for tracking people missing in the woods.",
      "question": "What does the second sentence do?",
      "options": [
        "It makes a contrast.",
        "It restates an idea found in the first.",
        "It states an effect.",
        "It gives an example."
      ],
      "answer": "It gives an example."
    },
    {
      "type": "multiple-choice",
      "passage": "Paris, France, is a city that has always been known as a center of artistic and cultural expression. In the 1920s, Paris was home to many artists and writers from around the world who became famous, such as Picasso and Hemingway.",
      "question": "What does the second sentence do?",
      "options": [
        "It reinforces the first.",
        "It states an effect.",
        "It draws a conclusion.",
        "It provides a contrast."
      ],
      "answer": "It reinforces the first."
    },
    {
      "type": "multiple-choice",
      "passage": "Studies show that the prevalence of fast-food restaurants corresponds with the rates of obesity in both children and adults. Obesity is now on the rise in countries outside the U.S., where fast food restaurants are becoming more common.",
      "question": "How do the two sentences relate?",
      "options": [
        "They express roughly the same idea.",
        "They contradict each other.",
        "They present problems and solutions.",
        "They establish a contrast."
      ],
      "answer": "They express roughly the same idea."
    },
    {
      "type": "multiple-choice",
      "passage": "Compared with the rest of the country, North Dakota has a thriving economy, making it a place where more people want to live. Winters in North Dakota are inhospitable, with average temperatures in January ranging from 2 degrees Fahrenheit to 17 degrees.",
      "question": "What does the second sentence do?",
      "options": [
        "It reinforces the first.",
        "It explains what is stated in the first.",
        "It contradicts the first.",
        "It analyzes a statement made in the first."
      ],
      "answer": "It contradicts the first."
    },
    {
      "type": "multiple-choice",
      "passage": "Some stores are testing a new checkout system that allows shoppers to use their mobile phones to scan items as they walk through stores and pay at self-service kiosks, skipping the cashiers' lines. The new mobile checkout system is intended to reduce long lines and customer wait times in stores.",
      "question": "What does the second sentence do?",
      "options": [
        "It expands on the first.",
        "It states an effect.",
        "It contrasts with the first.",
        "It gives an example."
      ],
      "answer": "It expands on the first."
    },
    {
      "type": "multiple-choice",
      "passage": "According to the American Sleep Disorders Association, the average teenager needs around 9.5 hours of sleep per night, possibly because critical growth hormones are released during sleep. The average adult requires between six and eight hours of sleep per night for optimal health and productivity.",
      "question": "How do the two sentences relate?",
      "options": [
        "They establish a contrast.",
        "They contradict each other.",
        "They reinforce each other.",
        "They provide a problem and solution."
      ],
      "answer": "They establish a contrast."
    }
  ]
}
